那么现在我们已经明白了Service(服务)的工作机制
So now that we understand how services work,
下面我们来看看Android如何划分程序的优先级。
let's review how Android determines your app's priority. App
程序的优先级主要分为三种。
priority is divided into three general buckets. Critical,
critical(重要)、high(高)、low(低)。而程序都在各自的优先级中
high, and low. Within each bucket the apps are
按顺序进行排队。
prioritized in a queue. With the app that's
程序的优先级处在最低级并且时间最长的
been at the lowest priority for the longest, the
会第一个被运行。Critical程序是指那些活跃的程序。
first to be executed. Critical apps are those that
这些程序处在前台，正与用户发生交互行为
are active. They're in the foreground, interacting with users.
包括在前台的activity和运行在前台的service
That includes activities in the foreground and apps
属于高优先级的包括可见的activity
running foreground services. High priority apps, include any visible
和那些带有运行着的服务的程序
activities and any application with a running service.
优先级比结束前台程序、释放可见activity
While less impactful than killing a foreground app, destroying
或者结束服务稍低一些级别的也会通知用户
visible activities or cancelling services running tasks like
比如程序在后台进行更新。
background updates it's still going to be noticeable to users.
所以系统仅仅会在可用资源极度缺乏的时候
So, the system will only kill them in
才会释放他们。而处于后台的程序(他们处于优先级的最低级别)
an extreme resource crunch. Apps in the background though,
他们是整个程序优先级大部队中的基层干事
they're the red shirted ensigns of the app priority
任何后台程序都会根据需要被裁掉(也就是释放程序资源）
landing party. Any background app will be killed as
释放顺序是最早转到后台的程序最先被释放掉
needed, in a last seen, first killed order, in
以此来释放资源供给更高优先级的程序
order to help support the higher priority apps. I like
我喜欢把这个归结为
to think of this as the three laws of
Android资源管理的三大法则。法则一：
Android resource management. Law one, Android will keep all apps
Android会保证所有与用户进行交互的程序运行平顺。
that interact with the user running smoothly. Android will
法则二：Android会保持所有可见的activity或者正在运行的服务所占用的资源。
keep all apps with visible activities or running services running.
除非他们对资源的占用违反了法则一。法则三：Android会保持所有转入后台的程序的资源
Unless doing so violates the first law. And third, Android will keep all
除非做样做违反了
apps in the background running, unless this
法则一和法则二
violates the first or second laws. So
所以当你知道这些后，再来看看这几个程序。
with all of that in mind, consider these four apps. What do you
你觉得根据系统规则，他们的优先级是怎么样的呢？
think is the priority order of each of these apps, according to the system.